Jay Umesh Gurnani

33 Botany Street• Randwick, NSW 2031

Phone: 0412522799 • E-Mail: jay.gurnani@gmail.com • Website: http://jaygurnani.github.io

• LinkedIn: https://au.linkedin.com/in/jay-gurnani • Nationality: Australian



SUMMARY

I graduated from the University of New South Wales with a Bachelor in Computer Science and I am currently pursuing a Masters of Information Technology at the same university. With 4 years of professional programming experience, I am able to develop complex solutions and communicate them to all levels of the organization. Colleagues know me as quick learner, an avid enthusiast for new technology and thinker who applies new computing paradigms for solving complex problems.

OBJECTIVE

As a young data engineer, I am seeking employment with a company where technology is a key area of focus and I can utilize my skills in new technologies to help the company meet its goals.

KEY SKILLS

Technical Skills:

Technology	Competence
Microsoft .NET 4.5 Framework (C# & VB.Net)	Expert
SQL 2012, SQL2014, SSIS	Expert
XLST	Expert
Java 7, Perl	Expert
JavaScript, AngularJS, jQuery, HTML	Strong
Python, PowerShell, R	Strong
Android SDK	Strong
CSS, LESS, BootStrap	Elementary
Hibernate Framework, Apache Hadoop	Elementary
Apache Maven, Adobe Flex, Sencha Touch	Elementary

Soft Skills:

Skill	Competence
Languages – English, Chinese (Mandarin)	Native fluency
Languages – Hindi	Elementary fluency
Team Management Systems (TMS)	Proficient
Agile Methodology/SCRUM	Proficient
Written and communication skills	Proficient

Jay Umesh Gurnani

33 Botany Street® Randwick, NSW 2031

Phone: 0412522799 • E-Mail: jay.gurnani@gmail.com • Website: http://jaygurnani.github.io

• LinkedIn: https://au.linkedin.com/in/jay-gurnani • Nationality: Australian



EXPERIENCE

UNIVERSITY OF NEW SOUTH WALES (UNSW) • Sydney, Australia Researcher - Networked System and Security Group

Aug 2016 - Present

Responsibilities:

Building a Drone Energy Model with Professor Mahbub Hassan's team

Proiects:

Master's Thesis: Tetherless Small Cell Base Stations using UAV Platforms.

Technologies:

Java, Android SDK, R, Python

PRICEWATERHOUSECOOPERS (PWC) • Sydney, Australia

Jan 2015 - Aug 2016

.NET Developer & Lead SQL Developer - Enterprise Performance Solutions (EPS) Division

Responsibilities:

- Based on Client specifications, built and designed enterprise web applications for multiple 6 month projects (front end and back
- Subject-matter expert on SQL performance tuning (25+ Developers) for enterprise systems
- Technical code reviewer for backend and middle tier code (25+ Developers)
- Mentored, trained and performance reviewed 3 interns
- Lead a team of 2 developers to load and performance enterprise web applications

Achievements:

- Received "Outstanding" rating for previous financial year
- Released 3 versions of the in-house Enterprise Software
- Initiated the Cross-Brower project resulting in a 2 year undertaking by EPS

Projects:

- Proof of concept for architecture automation and web application configuration using **Puppet**
- Proof of concept for replacing IE's XML Data Islands in legacy web applications
- Performance testing using JMeter and Visual Studio Load Test
- Improving SQL query performance across all systems
- Upgraded legacy web applications using Adobe Flex
- Architected and built software to manage the movement of enterprise data using SQL Replication and SSIS

Technologies:

SQL, .NET, AngularJS, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Adobe Flex, Visual Studio Load Test, **JMeter**

Jan 2013 - Dec 2014

PRICEWATERHOUSECOOPERS (PWC) • Sydney, Australia Graduate - Enterprise Performance Solutions (EPS) Division

Responsibilities:

Rotated among the Development, Business Analyst, Infrastructure Support and Business Intelligence teams to learn how each team operated with regard to the software development cycle

Projects:

- * Rewrote legacy web enterprise applications using .NET 4.5 and iQuery (1 year project)
- Released 4 versions of the enterprise web application

Technologies:

SQL, .NET, iQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, **PowerShell**

Achievements:

- Awarded the PwC Values and Recognition Award for quickly learning the Sencha Touch Framework and fixing critical Sencha bugs on a short timeframe
- Received "Outstanding" rating for 2 previous financial years
- Automated various process through PowerShell, SQL and Perl
- Improved cross team technical knowledge sharing by documenting the technologies and the designs each team uses

Jay Umesh Gurnani

33 Botany Street Randwick, NSW 2031

Phone: 0412522799 E-Mail: jay.gurnani@gmail.com Website: http://jaygurnani.github.io

• LinkedIn: https://au.linkedin.com/in/jay-gurnani• Nationality: Australian



ACADEMICA SINICA • Taipei, Taiwan Intern Ruby on Rails Developer – Development Team

Responsibilities:

- Worked on outstanding tickets to improve client-facing web applications (8 Developers)
- Responsible for all Chinese English translations for all in-house developed software

Projects:

Upgraded the UI for backend ticket tracking systems

Sep 2010 - Feb 2011 & Nov 2011 - Feb 2012

Achievements:

- Streamlining UI code to allow for better coding standards and quality
- Introduced Atlassian's FishEye for SVN Commit visualizations

Technologies:

Ruby on Rails, Linux, PrototypeJS

GOLD ARCH INTERNATIONAL PRESCHOOL • Guangzhou, China Full stack developer

Responsibilities:

- Liaised with client to gather business requirements
- Sole Business Analyst, Infrastructure support and Developer (1 year project)

Projects:

 Designed and built Gold Arch International Preschool's Website from ground up

Achievements:

- Built the website using Adobe Dreamweaver
- Learnt elementary design skills using Adobe Photoshop to meet client's needs

Technologies:

HTML, CSS, Adobe Photoshop, PHP

EDUCATION

MASTER OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

University of New South Wales • Sydney, Australia • High Distinction Average Key Area of Focus: Big Data Technologies

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

University of New South Wales • Sydney, Australia • Credit Average

University of Illinois • Champaign, IL, USA

July 2015 - Present

Aug 2007 - Aug 2008

Aug 2009 - Nov 2012

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft 70-461: Querying SQL Server May 2015

Score: 91/100

Algorithms (Coursera)

July 2014

IKM Test: Microsoft .NET Framework 4.5 Programming using C# Aug 2016

Score: 82/100 (Strong proficiency)

AWARDS

PwC Values and Recognition

Awarded for quickly learning the Sencha Touch Framework and fixing critical Sencha bugs

June 2014